来呀 德拉克斯 一起跳舞
Come on, Drax, dance.
白痴才跳舞
Only idiots dance.
我跟你说过几万次了 收起你的毛熊爪子 别碰我的随身听!
I told you a million times, you keep your grubby raccoon hands off my Zune!
我也跟你说过几万次了 我特么不是浣熊！
I told you a million times, I'm not a damn raccoon.
又开始了？
Again?
《银河护卫队3》
我爱你 卡魔拉
I love you, Gamora.
(虚无之地 银河护卫队总部)
那你怎么处理奎尔?
So what are you gonna do about Quill?
我? 为什么不是你?
Me?  Why not you?
我有情感创伤
I got emotionalistical issues.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
你为什么在天花板上走?
Why are you on the ceiling?
我想试试这双反重力靴在斜坡上是否管用
I wanted to see if these new gravity boots worked on a slope.
开始了
Here we go.
对不起
Sorry.
你得明白 你根本不是这块料
You must know you will never learn.
你觉得你能做得比我好吗?
You think you could do better?
是的
Dah.
用心灵遥控是作弊
Telekinesis is cheating!
那只是一块愚蠢的小石头
That's a stupid little pebble.
我自己用手也能做到  该死的
I can do that with my dang finger.
你这坏狗
You're a bad dog.
别那样对我说话
Do not say that to me.
你就是 你这坏狗
You are. You're a bad dog.
收回那句话  拜托 这样可不好
Take that back. Come on, that's not cool.
星云 你听到了吗?
Nebula, did you hear?
他说我是坏狗 而且拒绝收回这句话
He called me a bad dog and he refuse to take it back.
我不在乎 科斯莫
I don't care, Cosmo.
彼得还好吗
Is Peter okay?
- 我不知道 - 你打算怎么办？
- I don't know. - What are you going to do?
我？ 他可是你的哥哥
Me?  He's your brother.
这不是重点 他从来都不听我的
It doesn't matter, he still doesn't listen to me.
是啊 自从卡魔拉死后  他就一直闷闷不乐
Yeah, he has been pretty mopey ever since Gamora died.
她没死
She's not dead.
她只是不记得过去那几年的事了
She just doesn't remember anything from the past few years.
为什么我都不知情
Nobody tells me nothing.
曼提斯 你为什么不摸摸他? 你懂的 让他开心点
Mantis, why don't you just touch him? You know, make him happy.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
恶心
Gross!
不 不是那样的 是用她的超能力触摸他
No, not like that. Touch him with her powers.
操纵朋友的情感是不对的
It is wrong to manipulate the feelings of friends.
上次你让我爱上了我的袜子算什么？
What about that time you made me fall in love with my sock?
好吧 但那真的很好玩
Well, that was funny.
我猜我们只好找人抚摸他了
I guess it's back to one of us touching him the other way.
也许我们应该抽签决定
Maybe we should draw straws.
想都别想 德拉克斯
No one ever meant that, Drax.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?!
你去哪儿了 松鼠?
Where did you go, Squirrel?
趴下
On the ground!
那个疯子是谁?
Who is that maniac?
某个拿着射线枪的超级混蛋吧  我他妈的怎么知道呢
Some super-douche with ray gun hands! I don't freakin' know.
谁扔我的?
Who threw this thing at me?
闭嘴
Shut up.
幼稚
Baby.
挑个跟你个头差不多大的打
Pick on someone your own size.
彼得
Peter!
我们需要医疗包
We need med packs.
星云
Nebula.
滚开
Piss off!
好疼啊
That hurts.
可怜虫
What a pity.
不
No!
我只是激活了医疗包
All I did was activate the med pack!
拿走它  快点
Get them off! Now!
哦 见鬼
Oh, hell.
- 我们得送他去医务室 - 医务室被毁了
- We need to get him to the med bay. - It's destroyed.
飞船上还有一个
There's one on the ship!
把他缝合好 然后 和第89批剩下的 一起转移
Stitch him up and transfer him in with the rest of batch 89.
没事的
It's okay.
你现在和我们在一起
You're here with us now.
嘿, 那个新来的家伙是谁?
Hey, who's the new guy?
你是什么动物?
What kind of thing are you?
你脸上好像戴了个面具
You've got like, a mask on your face.
面具 眼睛 脸 嘴巴
Mask, eyes, face, mouth.
疼吗?
Does it hurts?
没事的 朋友
It's okay, friend.
不要让他们吓到你
Don't let them scare you.
疼
Hurts...
没事的
It's okay.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
自杀开关?
A kill switch?
一个装置
A device.
一旦有东西进入他的身体  装置就自动毁灭
Set to destruct if anyone goes poking around inside him.
就算我们用医疗包也不行
Or even if we use the med packs.
为什么火箭体内会有毁灭开关?
Why would a Rocket have a kill switch?
显然 有人认为他是一项专利技术 于是派那个金色疯子来抓他
Apparently someone considers him proprietary technology and sent that golden lunatic to get him.
如果我们给他做手术 他会死吗?
So he'll die if we operate on him?
- 如果不手术 他会死的 - 一定有其他办法绕过它
- And he'll die if we don't. - There has to be some way to bypass it.
好像有个密钥可以覆盖死亡开关
It looks like there's a passkey that can override the kill switch.
你们有谁知道火箭的身世吗?
What do we know about where Rocket came from?
他一直不愿谈论这种事
He won't talk about it.
大部分技术都是由一家名为奥格集团的公司开发的
Much of the tech was developed by a company called OrgoCorp.
他们所有的东西都会有编码
And there's a code on all of it.
89P13
89P13.
他大概还剩下48小时
He's got maybe 48 hours.
- 你要去哪里?  - 奥格集团肯定有记录 对吧?
- Where are you going? - OrgoCorp had to have records, right?
也许它能帮我们解除这个死亡开关 拯救火箭
Maybe it'll have a way for us to override the kill switch and save Rocket.
他们不会就这么把信息给我们的
They won't just give us that information.
所以我们才要闯进去
Well, that's why we're gonna break in.
挡我者死
And kill anyone who gets in our way!
- 不可以杀人  - 就杀几个
- Not kill anyone.  - Kill a few people.
- 一个都不行 - 杀一个怎么样 一个没人爱的那种
- Kill no people. - Kill one guy, one stupid guy who no one loves.
现在气氛都让你搞砸了
Now you're just making it sad.
克拉格林 科斯莫 在我们回来之前看好虚无之地  最多两天
Kraglin, Cosmo, I need you to keep watch over Knowhere till we're back. Couple of days tops.
- 是  舰长  - 是  朋友
- Aye, cap'n. - Aye, comrade.
- 收回你刚才说的“我是坏狗”的话  - 不
- Take back what you said that I'm a bad dog. - Nope.
我知道你不是故意说我是坏狗的
I know you don't really think that I'm a bad dog.
- 快点收回那句话   - 我是故意的
- Can you please take it back? - I will not.
我找到了奥格集团的坐标
I located the coordinates for OrgoCorp.
我有个熟人在那 也许他们能帮我们混进去
I think I have a contact near there. Maybe they can help us get in.
联系他呗
Contact him.
我们去拯救朋友吧
Let's go save our friend.
有朋友真好
It's good to have friends.
(阿雷特实验室  反地球)
可怜的宝贝
My poor baby.
妈妈  好疼
Mama, it hurts.
- 你拿到了吗？ - 他没有  陛下
- Do you have it? - He does not, sire.
我警告过你 至高进化
I tried to warn you, High Evolutionary.
这些守护者比你想象的更强大
These Guardians are more powerful than you think.
或许你只是高估了自己的价值 大祭司
Or perhaps you simply overestimate your own value, High Priestess.
毫无疑问 我的设计有缺陷
No doubt, a flaw's on top of my own design.
我创造你们只是为了研究美学
I created you lot as merely an aesthetic experiment.
漂亮的皮囊
Beautiful numbskulls.
但你的自尊心失控了 说“啊”
But your egos have run wild. Say "ah."
而这个人本应是个术士
And this one was meant to be the Warlock.
他们那一群的佼佼者
The apogee of their people.
是你提前把亚当从茧里取出来的 陛下
You removed Adam from his cocoon early, my liege.
他还是个孩子
He is still a child.
不 除了这些 他还有点问题
No, there's something wrong with him even outside all that.
是的 我确实有点问题  我被刺伤了你这个该死的
Yes, there's something wrong with me. I was stabbed, you extraordinary phallus
他什么都不懂 陛下 我们听从您的吩咐
He doesn't know any better. We shall do whatever you require, my liege.
你很早就知道89P13的存在  却不提醒我
You knew of 89P13's existence for years without alerting me.
你违背了我的指示
That's not what I require!
对不起 陛下
I'm sorry, my liege.
找到89P13 把它给我
Find 89P13 and return it to me.
否则 我会摧毁你们的整个文明
Or, I will destroy your entire civilization
作为你们的创造者  我有这个权利
as is my right as your maker!
你明白吗?
Do you understand?
是的  陛下
Yes. Sire
闪人
Toodle-do
这么多年过去了 89P13是如何存活下来的 提尔？
How did 89P13 survive after all these years, Theel?
它一直都很聪明 陛下
It was always clever, sire.
是的 所以我得马上抓住它
Yes, that's exactly why I want it now.
- 当然 - 它的大脑
- Of course. - Its brain.
你说啥就是啥 陛下
That is the only reason, sire.
但你真的相信索维林人能抓到它吗？
But are you really trusting the Sovereign to retrieve it?
它们只是备用计划
They're merely a backup.
我想我知道他们要去哪里了
I believe I know where they're going.
(奥格集团总部)
它是个生物体
It's bioformed.
它不是建造出来的 而是自己长出来的
Instead of being built, it's grown from living matter.
整个建筑被三层高强度的等离子安全护盾包围着
The structure is surrounded by three impenetrable plasmic security shields.
想闯进这地方可不容易 星爵
It's not gonna be easy to break into this place, Star-Lord.
无所谓 我是职业的 记得吗
Doesn't have to be easy. I was a professional thief, remember?
我会一个接一个地发出干扰信号
I'll jam the signals one at a time.
她一生气就会叫我星爵
She calls me Star-Lord when she's mad at me.
她对谁都是一副臭脸
She's always mad at everyone.
因为我喝醉了
It's because I was drunk.
她说得对  如果我没有喝酒…
She's right. If I haven't been drinking...
也许火箭… 对不起
Maybe Rocket... I'm sorry.
没关系 毕竟他是你最好的朋友
It's okay, he's your best friend.
第二好的朋友
Second best friend.
我身边的人都死了  我的母亲 勇度…
Everyone around me dies. My mother, Yondu...
- 卡魔拉  - 卡魔拉没有死
- Gamora... - Gamora isn't dead.
她没死  你想吃核桃吗?
She is to us. Do you want a zargnut?
谢谢你
Thank you.
第一个护盾 准备
First shield, set.
三 二  一
Three, two, one.
- 彼得 - 什么?
- Peter. - What?
你在地球上还有家人  你有没有想过回去看看他们?
You had family on Earth. And you never wanted to go back and see them?
你是我妹妹   你就是我的家人 这就够了
You're my sister. That's all the family I want or need.
而且地球只剩下我外祖父一个人了好吗?  他是个很难相处的人
Besides, it's probably just my grandpa, okay? He was a pretty hard guy.
- 不过 你不觉得他… - 什么?
- Still, don't you think he... - What?
你被掠夺者绑架了  就在那天他失去了他女儿
You were abducted by Ravagers the same day he lost his daughter.
对 他很伤心 我妈死了 他吼我 把我推出房间
Oh yeah, he was upset. My mom died, he screamed at my face and he pushed me out of the room!
他可能只是想保护你
He was probably just trying to protect you.
- 你在说什么? - 什么?
- What are you talking about? - What?
我说的是我生命中死去的人 你却老给我打岔
I'm talking about the people in my life who died, and you're talking about this?
第二个护盾 准备
Second shield, set.
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
我只是说 你为啥从来没想过回地球去看看他过得好不好
I'm only saying you've never even gone to see if he's okay.
他可能还活着
He could still be alive.
我的外祖父? 他应该有90多岁了
My grandpa? He'd be like, 90- something years old.
所以他可能还活着
So he could still be alive.
地球上的人50岁左右就会死去
People on Earth die when they're like 50.
他们50岁就死了?
They die when they're 50?
我不知道 差不多就是这样
I don't know. Something like that.
那生下来有什么意义？
What's even the point of being born?
没错
Exactly.
你快要死了吗？
Are you about to die?
我还没有50岁
I'm not 50!
重点是 我们严重跑题了
The point is, I wasn't talking about any of this.
第三个护盾 准备
Third shield, set.
三 二 一
Three, two, one.
好吧  不是所有的事情 都得以你为主角  来展开
Well, not everything is about what you are talking about.
我只是说 你很伤心 是因为很多你在乎的人  都离开了你
And I'm only saying you are upset because so many people you cared about have left you.
但你也离开了某些人
But you also left someone.
好吧 我想要一个核桃
And maybe I wanted a zargnut.
太迟了  都吃完了
Too late. They're all gone.
我们为什么还没通过呢?
Why didn't we go through?
我们通过了  这不是护盾
We did. It's not the shield.
哦  见鬼
Oh, hell.
是掠夺者
Ravagers.
嘿 伙计们 你们就要被联合掠夺者登船了
Hey guys, you're about to be boarded by the United Ravagers.
你们可以交出任何值钱的东西 然后活下去 或者你们可以去死
You can surrender and turn over any stuff worth anything and live. Or you can die.
这取决于你们
It's up to you.
德拉克斯 不不 德拉克斯
Drax, no, no, no! Drax!
伙计们 是我 彼得奎尔  我是你们中的一员 记得吗?
Guys, it's me. Peter Quill. I'm one of you, remember?
等一下
Hold on!
- 我们与人有约  - 一个约会
- We have an appointment. - We have an appointment.
- 和谁？ - 和卡魔拉
- With who? - With Gamora.
和卡魔拉  什么
With Gamora. What?
你来早了
You're early.
这些是什么
What are these?
奥格集团的制服
OrgoCorp uniforms.
你们得穿上这个才能在不引人注意的情况下混进奥格
You've got to wear these to move through the Orgo without attracting attention.
我不喜欢这颜色
This isn't my color.
你说什么
What did you say?
它和我的眼睛不搭配
It clashes with my eyes.
快穿上
Put it on!
星云 你为什么不告诉我你联系的是卡魔拉?
Nebula, why would you not tell me that you've been in contact with Gamora?
因为我不想吓坏你
Because I didn't want you to get freaked out.
- 被吓坏？ - 就像这样
- Freaked... out?! - Like that.
卡魔拉 我们非常感谢你的帮助
Gamora, we're grateful for your help.
我这么做不是出于好心
I'm not doing this out of the kindness of my heart.
我这样做只是为了我妹妹承诺的十万块钱
I'm doing this for the hundred thousand units my sister promised.
所以你现在加入掠夺者了?
So you're a Ravager now?
穿上制服
Put on the uniform.
从没想过你会成为掠夺者
Never pictured you as the Ravager type.
你是谁来着?
Who are you again?
哦 天哪
Oh, man...
奥格集团拥有银河系最先进的基因技术知识产权
OrgoCorp is in possession of some of the most advanced cybergenetic IP in the galaxy.
他们被致命的奥格警卫保护着
So they're heavily guarded by the deadly Orgosentries.
现在 我知道你们没有证件可以进出
Now I know you don't have documentation to dock.
所以你们必须自己想办法进去
So you're gonna have to get in there on your own.
进去后 卡魔拉就会带你们去找记录文件
Once in, Gamora is gonna lead you to the records.
也许你们能在记录里找到密钥  控制死亡开关
Where maybe you can find the passkey to override the kill switch.
帮助你们救小刺猬
And help you save the hedgehog.
但如果你们遇到麻烦
But if you get into trouble,
我们将无法保释你们出来
we will not be able to bail you out.
是
Yes.
是  当然了
Yes, of course.
它的能力突飞猛进
Its functioning has skyrocketed.
没错 P13  非常好
That's correct, P13. Very good.
这就是新世界
That's the new world.
反地球
Counter-Earth.
一旦实验准备好 你们就会去那里生活
Where the experiments will go once they're ready.
- 蓝色的  - 那是天空
- It blue. - That's the sky.
天空
Sky.
- 火箭  - 是的
- Rocket. - Yes, it is.
什么声音?
What sounds?
那是音乐
That's music.
- 我们喜欢吗？  - 喜欢
- We like it? - We do.
这张唱片已有5000多年的历史了
This recording is over 5,000 years old.
翻译过来就是...
Which translated, is...
不要安于现状  要勇于超载自己
Be not as you are, but as you should be.
这是我们的神圣使命
It's our sacred mission
把我们周围不和谐的声音
to take the cacophony of sounds around us
变成一首歌
and turn it into a song.
把像你这样不完美的生物体
To take an imperfect clump of biological matter such as you,
转化成为……完美的生物
and transform it into something... perfect.
我们已经成功了一半 不是吗?
And we're halfway there, aren't we?
跟我来 P13
Come with me, P13.
我想给你看样东西
I'd like to show you something.
我们的目标只有一个…
We have but a single quest...
创造完美的物种
To create the perfect species,
以及完美的社会
and the perfect society.
你  P13
You, P13,
是第89批的一部分
are part of batch 89.
但这里 是第90批
But here, with batch 90,
我开发了一个流程 通过这个流程
I've developed a process by which I can guide
我可以引导任何生物体 在一瞬间就能经历数百万年进化
any organism through millions of years of programmed evolution changes, in a moment.
现在看来
See now...
这就是问题所在
There's the rub.
出于某种原因 这些标本
For some reason, these specimens
在其系统中产生了过量的微胺蛋白
are also overproducing the legobeta microsamino protein in their systems.
这就导致他们 嗯…
Causing them to be, well...
很暴力  我们不喜欢这个
Violent.  We don't like it.
一个乌托邦不可能让它的居民互相残杀 是吧？
A utopia cannot have its denizens murdering one another, can it?
他们不恁
They can't.
- 不能  - 不能
- Can't. - Can't.
提尔
Theel.
他们设定的初衷是平和的 就像你一样
They're programmed to be peaceful, like you.
但出于某种原因 它没起作用
But for some reason, it's not catching.
构造过滤器
Tectonic filters.
什么
What?
它们抑制甘氨酸来源
They suppresaliding the glycusoride sources.
然后 噗 噗 噗…
And then, boop, boop, boop...
存在残余畸形
Absisting residual deformity.
然后  他们 产生了
And then, they, make, um...
- 你所说的那个什么? - 微胺蛋白
- What do you say? - The legobeta microsamino proteins.
是的 就是那个
Yeah, thems.
然后 导致了愤怒
And then, angry turtleses.
那里 那是减压室
There, that's the decompression chamber.
锁定
Lock in.
前进
Go.
启用重力靴和手套
Activate gravity boots and gloves.
星云  上
Nebula, go.
所以你真的什么都不记得了?
So you really don't remember anything?
比如说呢
Like what?
- 和我们在一起很久了 - 没有
- Bunch of time with us. - No.
- 好吧,我们……  - 我们什么都不是
- Well, we were... - We weren't anything.
- 你和我... - 那个人是我未来的另一个版本
- You and me... - That person was some alternate future version of me.
不是我
Wasn't me.
我们彼此相爱
We loved each other.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我知道你什么都不记得了
I know you don't remember any of it...
你是我的一切
You were everything to me.
我好想你
And I miss you.
非常想
So much.
也许...
And maybe...
如果你愿意考虑一下
Maybe if you open yourself up to it...
- 我们有可能… - 我不这么认为 奎因
- There's a possibility... - I don't think so, Quinn.
- 奎尔 - 奎尔
- Quill. - Quill.
我可不这么认为
I don't think so.
但我想说的是
But what I'm trying to say...
彼得 你知道这是公开频道 对吧?
Peter, you know this is an open line, right?
- 什么? - 我们听到了你说的每一句话
- What? - We're listening to everything you're saying.
感觉很痛苦
And it is painful.
而你现在才告诉我？
And you're just telling me now?
我们希望你能自己停下来
We were hoping it would stall on its own.
但我点的是私密频道
But I switched it over to private.
你按了什么颜色的按钮
What color button did you push?
蓝色  对应蓝色服装
Blue. For the blue suit.
- 哦  不  - 蓝色是公开频道
- Oh, no. - Blue is the open line for everyone.
橙色才代表蓝衣
Orange is for blue.
- 什么？ - 黑色代表橙衣
- What? - Black is for orange.
黄色代表绿衣   绿色代表红衣
Yellow is for green. Green is for red.
红色代表黄衣
And red is for yellow.
不  黄色代表黄衣
No, yellow is for yellow.
绿色代表红衣  红色代表绿衣
Green is for red. Red is for green.
- 我不这么认为  - 试试看
- I don't think so. - Try it, then.
你好
Hello!
- 你说得对 - 我他妈的怎么可能知道这些？
- You were right. - How the hell am I supposed to know all of that!?
看起来很直观
Seems intuitive.
我们能继续拯救朋友吗?
Can we get back to saving our friend?
让干扰机准备更换防护罩
Get that jammer ready to change the shield.
伙计们
Guys?
你想谈谈甜蜜驾驶吗？加速度会压垮你的脊椎
You wanna talk about a sweet ride? The acceleration would crush your spine.
它有全新的燃能核心 你知道我在说什么吗?
It's got that brand new Fusilux core. You know what I'm talking about?
- 哦 是的 -真的吗? 因为这个词是我瞎编的
- Oh, yeah.  - Really? Because I just made that up.
哦 我以为你说的是别的东西
Oh, I thought you said something else.
卡佳大师
Master Karja.
- 不 你没有 - 我有  我有
- No, you didn't. - I did... I did.
卡尔佳大师 白色翼部的某个地方似乎有个缺口
Master Karja, there appears to be a physical breach in the white wing somewhere.
会不会是个小故障?
Could it be a glitch?
也许吧
Maybe?
我正在访问眼睛
I'm accessing the eye.
看看能不能找到它
I'll see if I can locate it.
减压室内有某种异常情况  最好去看看 大师
There's some sort of anomaly in the decompression chamber. Best to check it out, Master.
这就去
On it.
快点
Hurry.
这些放哪？
Where do we put these?
这里  把它们藏在这个储物柜里 直到我们撤离
Here! Hide them in this locker until we leave.
快点
Hurry.
那是什么鬼东西？伙计们
What the hell was that, guys?
你们在开玩笑吗？
Are you kidding me?
- 什么？  - 一个软木塞瓶盖刚好碰到卫星
- What? - A neutral cork just hit the satellite.
它在墙上烧了一个洞  你们这些天才没采取任何预防措施就把门打开了?
It's burning a hole thru the wall. You geniuses just throw the door open without any proper precautionary procedure?
什么措施 兄弟
What procedure, bro?
哦 想让我们帮你读读操作手册吗 兄弟？
Oh, you want us to read the manual for you too, bro?
你可能会杀了翼部的所有人
You could have killed everyone in the wing.
没错 你们这些白痴
Exactly, you idiots!
我也很生气
I'm angry, too.
哦  不
Oh, no.
你没看到我们身上穿的这些正宗的机械师制服吗？
Can't you see these authentic mechanic uniforms we're wearing on our bodies?
比其他颜色更能搭配我们的肤色
That blend in with some of our skin tones better than others?
对不起 我的朋友 他是老板的侄子 他有点...
Excuse my friend. He's the boss' nephew. He's a little...
是的 我…我也有一个这种的
Yeah, I... I got one of those too.
这一个嘛  这一个 我喜欢 我很自豪...
This one? This one, I love. I'm so proud of...
你做得很好 为你感到骄傲
You're doing great. So proud of you.
但这一个嘛 我只能...
But this one... I just...
他做的每件事都让我抓狂
Everything he does drives me crazy.
- 我以为你说的是别的东西  - 闭嘴
- I thought you said something else. - Shut up.
我发誓我要掐死他
I swear I'm gonna throttle him.
我会因谋杀白痴入狱的 我会的
I'm gonna go to jail for murder. I am.
你们怎么这么快就到了？
How did you guys get here so fast?
老实跟你说吧 还好我们动作快 否则就完蛋了  谢天谢地
Gonna be honest with you, we just happened in before it burned all the way through, thankfully.
幸好你在这里
Good thing you were here.
好了 伙计们 收工吧
Alright guys, wrap it up.
看来我们都安全了
Looks like we're all clear here.
我们的太空服
Our spacesuits!
你把它们扔进了垃圾桶
You threw them in the contamination bin.
你一关门 它就会把东西排入太空
It expels stuff into space the moment you shut the door.
这在三分钟前可能是有用的信息
That would have been helpful information three minutes ago!
该死 曼提斯 你怎么就不好好想想?
Dammit, Mantis, why don't you ever think?
哦  我们又要假装生气了吗?
Oh, are we pretending to be angry again?
曼提斯  你这个混蛋
Mantis, you asshole!
伙计们 专心两秒钟
Guys, just focus for two seconds.
我们会找到别的出路的 而现在…
We'll find another way out of here. Right now...
我们得先救火箭的命
We need to save Rocket's life.
星云 奎因和我去查记录然后拿 密钥
Nebula, Quinn and I will get to the records and get the passkey.
小虫子和大笨蛋 通过电梯进入太空港 这样木头人就可以着陆 带我们离开这里
Bug and doofus, access the spaceport through the elevator so Tree can land and get us out of here.
- 哦 抱歉 - 没问题
- Oh, apologies. - No problem.
快去
Go.
这又不是我的错 我都不知道那东西是什么  都没人告诉我
It's not my fault I don't know what something is. No one ever tells me.
我甚至都不想来这里
I didn't even want to come here.
我要看看你的…
I'm gonna need to see your...
你无可救药地坠入爱河… 和他
You're hopelessly in love... with him.
哦 不
Oh, no...
你今天过得怎么样
How are you doing today?
我很好
I'm alright.
你叫什么名字？
What was your name again?
毁灭者 德拉克斯
Drax the Destroyer.
真是个可爱的名字
That's such a lovely name.
我来帮你开门
I'll get the door for you.
- 你回来的时候我还会在这里的 好吗? - 好的
- I'll be here when you come back out, okay? - Sure.
每次都这样
Every single time.
我的名字是布里特 斯诺特
My name is Brittle Snorte!
欢迎来到奥格集团总部
Welcome to OrgoCorp headquarters.
300多年来 奥格集团一直在全宇宙生产可控植入物和基因升级
For over 300 years OrgoCorp has been producing cybernetic implants and genetic upgrades across the universe.
在至高进化的注视下
Under the watchful eye of the High Evolutionary.
我们今天收到的警告 那两个人不符合描述吗？
That warning we got today. Don't those two match the description?
全体奥格警卫请注意
Attention all Orgosentries.
那个经理应该有权查看记录
That manager should have access to the records.
如果 密钥在这里 她可以帮我们拿
If the passkey is here, she can get it for us.
好的
All right.
- 我来处理这个 - 怎么做
- I'll handle this one. - How?
纯粹的星爵魅力
Pure Star-Lord charm.
我很高兴你能第一次看到这个
I'm excited that you get to see this again for the first time.
嗨 尤拉
Hi, Yura.
- 乌拉  - 哦 乌拉
- Ura.  - Oh, Ura.
- 嗨 - 嗨  我的名字叫派屈克 史威兹
- Hi. - Hi, my name is Patrick Swayze.
我注意你很久了
I've been noticing you for quite a while.
每当你觉得没人在看你的时候  你总会对自己微笑
And whenever you smile to yourself, when you think nobody is looking,
这笑容让我的每一天都变得更加明亮
it makes my everyday a bit brighter.
我们需要你的手 它是否在你身上由你自己选择
We need your hand, and it's your choice whether it's on your body, or not!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
她决不会上当的
She was never gonna fall for that.
她完全被我迷住了  伙计
She was totally into me, man.
我有点觉得你是个笨蛋
I kinda thought you were a douchebag.
哦  拜托
Oh, come on.
- 我们需要一份文件 - 什么文件？
- We need a file.  - What file?
89P13  那会是什么呢？
89P13. Would that be something?
- 不 - 那你对我们就没用了
- No.  - Then your use to us is over.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
听起来像是一个物种标签
Sounds like a species tag.
给我们看看
Show us!
我们所有的研究 都支持至高进化的  利他主义目标
All of our research supports the High Evolutionary's altruistic objective,
即创建一个乌托邦社会
of creating a utopian society.
那一定是太空港
That must be the spaceport.
这都是什么？
What is all this?
多年来使用奥格集团技术获得专利的物种
Species patented over the years using OrgoCorp tech.
奥格集团创建的每一个物种都有自己的档案
Every species OrgoCorp has created has its own individual file.
对此我很抱歉 听我说 这不是我们该做的事
I am so sorry about this. Listen to me, this is not the kinda thing we do.
哦 拜托 别再拐弯抹角了
Oh, please, stop it with the subtle jabs!
以前的你绝不会这么做的
Old you would've never done this.
你有一个比自己更高尚的目标 那就是帮助别人
You had a purpose higher than yourself, the calling to help people.
所以你才离开灭霸 组建了护卫队
That's why you left Thanos and formed the Guardians.
但我没有组建护卫队 也没怎么离开灭霸
Except I didn't form the Guardians and I barely left Thanos.
不管你爱的是谁
Whoever it was that you were in love with,
那不是我
it wasn't me.
这听起来更像她
It sounds more like her.
- 她？  - 啥？
- Her? - What?
- 太荒谬了… - 别把我扯进来
- That's ridiculous... - Do not drag me into this.
- 别闹了! - 什么?
- Knock it off!  - What?
别把我当成需要温暖的小狗
Don't look at me like a lost puppy needing a soft place to lie down!
我什么也没说
I didn't say anything.
我只是从来没有注意到你的眼睛那么黑亮
I just never noticed how black your eyes were.
它们被我父亲挖掉替换了
They were replaced by my father
为了折磨我
as a method of torture.
至少他选了一套漂亮的
He picked a pretty set.
那里
There.
那就是89P13的文件
That's the file for 89P13.
当心 当心
Heads up. Heads up.
哦  不
Oh, no.
走
Walk!
退出去
Stand down!
德拉克斯 我们应该逃跑
Drax, we should make a run for it.
- 或者我们可以打架 - 快跑
- Or we can fight. - Run.
- 打  - 跑
- Fight. - Run!
- 打 - 拿下他们
- Fight! - Take 'em!
我们该怎么办？
What are we going to do?
- 我有个计划  - 那是什么
- I got a plan.  - What is it?
你们所有人 跟我来
All of you, come with
所有人 放下武器 否则我打爆这女人的脑袋
Everybody, lower your weapons or I blow this woman's brain out!
这就是你的计划?
That's the plan?
你是一只小猫咪
You're a kitty cat.
你想跳舞
You feel like dancing.
暴怒
Violent rage.
放下你们的武器
Lower your weapons!
现在杀了那根胡萝卜 杀鸡儆猴
Now kill that one that looks like a carrot to show we mean business.
老天 以前的卡魔拉太狠了!
God! Past Gamora's just mean!
她一直都是这样 而我却成了坏人
She was always like that, and yet I was the bad guy.
我们不会杀任何人的
We are not killing anyone!
后退
Back off!
格鲁特 把飞船开过来  马上
Groot, bring the Bowie to us. Now!
- 我很抱歉 尤拉 - 哦 拜托
- I'm so sorry about this, Ura. - Oh, please.
我们是来救我们朋友的  仅此而已
We're here to save the life of our friend. That is all.
我们付钱找她来带我们偷东西
We paid her to help us get in and get out.
你以为她有多高明 能神不知鬼不觉
You'd think that'd mean, "oh, I'm gonna help them do it in a way that no one knows what's happening."
没有，她竟然打算开枪 用武力上
But no. What she means is I'm gonna shoot people. Threaten people's lives.
闭嘴
Shut up!
现在我知道你可能在问“我为什么要信任她？”
And now I know you're probably asking "why would I trust her?" Well...
这是个好问题
That's a good question.
答案是
The answer is...
我们曾经相爱过
We used to be in love.
是的 她是我的女朋友 只是她不记得了 因为那不是她
Yeah, she was my girlfriend. Only she doesn't remember it because it wasn't her.
因为她爸爸把她从魔法悬崖上扔了下去 她死了
Because her dad threw her off a magic cliff and she died.
然后我发了脾气 几乎毁灭了半个宇宙
Then I lost my temper and nearly destroyed half the universe.
然后她回来了 从过去穿越来的  这就是她
And she came back. Out of the past. There she is.
所有穿越而来的人都死了 除了她  为什么？
Everyone else who died in the past stayed dead. Not her. Why?
是神奇悬崖吗？我不知道
Was it the magic cliff? I don't know.
我不是什么古怪的“无限宝石”科学家
I'm not some freakin' Infinity Stone scientist.
只是一个愚蠢的地球人 遇到了一个女孩 坠入了爱河
Just some dumbass Earth dude who met a girl, fell in love.
那个女孩死了
That girl died,
然后回来的时候却是个十足的混蛋
and then came back a total dick.
虽然漏掉了一些重要的信息 但是…
You left out some important information, but...
大致就是这样
That is the gist of it.
到安全舵上去
Get to the security helm.
知道了
Okay!
所有人都趴下 不然我们就打爆你的头
Everybody down on the floor or we blow your brains out.
嘿 嘿 嘿 我们不想
Hey, hey, hey, hey. We don't want any
哦 哦 我的天啊
Oh, oh, oh my God!
拜托 你能不能别这样
Come on! Will you please stop doing that?
快跑
Run.
德拉克斯
Drax!
趴在地上 把手举起来
Get on the ground, and show me your hands now.
欧拉
Ura...
请听我说 我们得带着这个离开这里
Please listen to me. We need to get out of here with this.
去救我最好朋友的命
To save my best friend's life.
如果你能让我们进入外面那些警卫的系统 他们是好人 就像你一样…
If you can get us into the systems of those sentries out there, they are good people, like you...
我敢肯定
I'm certain of it.
如果我有机会和他们谈谈
And if I just had an opportunity to speak to them...
他们是公司的走狗 你个白痴 他们不会听的
They're corporate shills, you idiot. They're not gonna listen.
如果我发自内心地对他们说话 他们会听的
They will listen if I speak to them from my heart.
乌拉
Ura...
拜托
please.
出来吧
Come out now!
该死的
Damn it!
停下
Stop!
你可以进去了
You are in.
- 告诉他们休战 - 是啊 我没那么傻
- Tell them your truce  - Yeah, I'm not that big of an idiot.
我只需要进入系统
I just needed to get into the system.
快走
Move it.
告诉过你她喜欢我
Told you she was into me.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
是啊 这看起来很酷
Yeah. That looked cool.
是天空吗
Is sky?
不
No.
那不是天空 那是天花板
That's not sky. That's a ceiling.
陛下正在为我们所有人创造一个新世界
Sire is making a new world for all of us.
当我们到达那里时
And when we get there,
那儿就会是天空
there will be sky,
它会很美丽的
and it will be beautiful.
直到永远
And forever.
我一直在想
I have been thinking.
想什么
About what?
哦 没什么特别的
Oh, nothing in particular.
但我想 既然你们是我最亲密的朋友
But I thought, since you guys are my closest friends,
也是我唯一的朋友
and my only friends,
你们也许有兴趣知道我在想什么
you might be interested in knowing that I have been thinking.
太酷了
That's cool.
我也一直在想
I've been thinking, too.
关于一些更奇特的东西
About something more singular.
当陛下带我们去新世界时
When sire moves us to the new world,
我们得有个名字
we're gonna need names.
我是说 89Q12…不是真正的名字
I mean, 89Q12... Not really a name.
所以
So...
我希望我的名字是…
I would like my name to be...
莱拉
Lylla.
这是一个漂亮的名字 莱拉
That's a pretty name, Lylla.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想我应该叫长牙
I think my name shall be Teefs.
因为尽管我们都有
Because although we all do have them,
但我的肯定是最突出的
mine are definitely the most prominent.
- 长牙  - 长牙
- Teefs. - Teefs.
- 莱拉. - 长牙.
- Lylla.  - Teefs.
我就想叫作 地板
Me be called Floor...
因为我躺在地板上
Because me is lying on floor.
你躺在地板上 所以你叫地板？
You're lying on a floor, so your name is Floor?
是呀
Yeah.
地板
Floor.
那么你呢 朋友
What about you, friend?
总有一天 我会制造出能飞的机器
Someday, I'm gonna make great machines that fly.
然后我和我的朋友们一起飞
And me and my friends are going to go flying together.
进入永远美丽的天空
Into the forever and beautiful sky.
莱拉 长牙 和地板
Lylla, and Teefs, and Floor...
还有我
And me.
火箭
Rocket.
有朋友真的很好
It really is good to have friends.
是啊
Yeah.
从这里开始切开
Start the incision here.
冷静
Keep calm.
- 别动 - 不行  它不停地移动
- Hold it still. - I can't. It won't stop moving!
为什么他从来没告诉过我们这些?
Why did he never tell us about any of this?
这比灭霸对我做的还要可怕
This is worse than what Thanos did to me.
但是 密钥呢?
But what about the passkey?
它在那里吗
Is it there?
不 但是今天有一个文件被删除了
No. But a file was removed today.
下载并删除了一百万个字符
Downloaded and deleted a million characters at length.
生物识别显示是这个人干的
The biometrics say it was this man.
记录员B2H6
Recorder B2H6.
我今天在档案室外面见到过这个人
I saw this guy outside of records today.
看起来像是至高进化的记录员
Looks like one of the High Evolutionary's recorders.
至高进化吗？
The High Evolutionary?
奥格集团的创始人？
The founder of OrgoCorp?
奥格集团只是为他的实验提供资金  而这些实验并不符合星系间的法律
OrgoCorp is just a way to fund his experiments that lie outside intergalactic laws.
他创造了整个社会
He's created whole societies.
泽罗尼亚人  动物人
Xeronians, the Animen.
- 索维林人  - 索维林人?
- Sovereign. - The Sovereign?
宇宙的各个角落都认为他是神
Corners of the universe consider him god.
-  我是格鲁特 - 是的
- I am Groot. - Yes.
是的, 什么? 他是格鲁特?
Yes, what? That he's Groot?
他说也许这个人把 密钥下载到了他头上的电脑里
He said maybe this man downloaded the passkey into the computer on his head.
那个东西  可以存储密钥
That can store the passkey.
如果我们找到他 我们就能拯救火箭
If we find him, we save Rocket.
至高进化的坐标
The High Evolutionary's coordinates.
把坐标输入导航系统
Put the coordinates in the nav.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你是在和我开玩笑吗?
Are you kidding me?
他想要的就是医务室里那只被掏空的浣熊
What he wants is that gutted badger in the med bay.
而你这是要直接告诉他吗？
And you're gonna bring it straight to him?
这几乎可以肯定  就是一个陷阱
It's almost certainly a trap.
如果你知道是陷阱 那么陷阱就不是陷阱了  而是一场较量
A trap isn't a trap if you know the trap is trying to trap you. It's a face-off.
如果你面对的是一个比你强大一千倍的人 那么较量就是一个陷阱
A face-off is a trap if you're facing off against a guy a thousand times more powerful than you.
你知道至高进化是谁吗
Do you know who the High Evolutionary is?
是的 他是个混蛋 解剖了我最好的朋友
Yeah, he's some dickhead who dissected my best friend.
第二好
Second best.
至高进化可不是你想惹就能惹得起的人
The High Evolutionary isn't someone you wanna think about messing with.
我们不会费那个脑子的  直接干他
We won't think about it when we do it.
你知道吗？我不在乎
You know what? I don't care.
把我送回掠夺者那里去吧 你们想做什么就去做吧
Just drop me off with the Ravagers and you go do whatever it is you wanna do.
我们没有时间做这事了
We don't have time for this.
我不是在问你 把我和我的人一起放下
I'm not asking you. Drop me off with my people now.
你的人
Your people?
掠夺者不是你的人  我才是该死的掠夺者 你不是
The Ravagers aren't your people. I'm a damn Ravager. You aren't.
听着 我知道你一直在寻找一个家 好吗?
Listen, I know you were always looking for a family, okay?
但我的卡魔拉 我爱过的人 她可没有和一群罪犯在一起
But my Gamora, the one I loved, she didn't find it with a group of criminals.
她是和我们找到家的
She found it with us.
我们这些关心你的人
People who care about you.
我知道你还是那个人
I know that's who you still are.
在你的内心深处…
Somewhere inside of you...
你到底害怕什么？要我为你做点什么吗?
What are you so afraid of in yourself, that I need to be something for you?
我才不在乎你那个版本的卡魔拉
I don't give a shit about your Gamora!
生活造就了我
Life made me me!
多亏了医疗舱里那只被掏空的浣熊 我得到了一些升级
I have a few upgrades courtesy of that gutted badger in the med bay.
我们不会冒着他的生命危险  为你行个方便的
And we are not risking his life to make yours more convenient.
- 我是你的家人 - 他也是
- I'm family.  - So is he.
去你的
Screw you.
去你们所有人的
Screw all of you.
在第一个护盾的外围发现了他
Found him on the outskirts of the first shield,
海盗补给船
pirating supply ships.
我真的很感激 好先生
I do appreciate this, good sir.
我很感激你对奥格警卫退休基金的捐款
And I appreciate your contribution to the Orgosentry retirement fund.
你的同事
Your associate.
一个叫卡魔拉的泽侯贝里人
A Zehoberi named Gamora.
- 她现在在哪里？ - 你从我这里得不到任何东西的
- Where is she now. - You'll get nothing from me!
哦 我们拭目以待 不是吗？
Oh, we'll see about that, won't we?
亚当
Adam.
Adam!
- 是的 妈妈  - 向他表明我们是认真的
- Yes, mother. - Show him we mean business.
我说让他看看我们是认真的
I said show him we mean business!
不是瓦解他
Not disintegrate him!
好吧  到底是什么生意要我向他表明？
Well, what business could we have shown him?
但现在他对我们毫无用处
But now he is of no use to us!
好吧 让我们问问这个人的朋友吧
Well let's just question the man's friend!
朋友？ 你觉得那是他朋友吗？那只是一只动物
Friend? You think that's a friend? It's an animal!
它看起来很伤心
He looks sad.
说实话 我真的不喜欢这种感觉
I really don't enjoy how that's making me feel, actually.
你的朋友是个白痴 我也有一个 我明白了
Your friend's a moron. I got one of those, too. I get it.
前哨吗
Outpost?
这是卡魔拉  你在吗?
This is Gamora. Are you there?
如果你能听到这个 请回话
If you can pick this up, come in.
前哨  请回话
Outpost, come in.
是的 卡魔拉
Yes, Gamora.
问候你
Salutations.
有事吗
May I help?
好吧 我需要你们来接我
Well, I need you guys to come pick me up.
我要上传我所在飞船的位置链接
I'm gonna upload the location link to the craft I'm on.
哦 我想我们可以安排
Oh, I think we can arrange that.
我让你说的话 你一定需要对他说
You need to say to him exactly what I told you to say.
你为什么不自己跟他说
Why don't you just say it?
从来没有人听我的
No one ever listens to me.
奎尔
Quill.
人生是一个池塘
Life is a pond.
你这辈子一个女人换另一个女人 她们就像池塘上的莲花叶
And you spent your entire life leaping from woman to woman, as if they are lily pads upon this great pond.
奎尔 也许你需要做的 …
Perhaps what you need to do, Quill...
就是学会游泳
... is learn to swim.
- 这很有道理 - 是的 有道理
- That actually made sense.  - Yes it made sense.
不 我是说 因为这是一种类比
No, I mean, 'cause that's sort of an analogy.
我不知道你还有这种能力…   我以为……
I didn't know that you were capable of that... I thought...
我知道很多比喻的 奎尔
I know lots of analogies, Quill.
类比 隐喻 等等
Analogies, metaphors, etcetera?
例如…
For instance...
卡魔拉的头就像一朵睡莲
Gamora's head is like a lily pad.
因为它是绿色的
Because it's green.
比喻
Analogy.
而且 看起来又蠢又浮躁
And also, stupid-looking and flappy.
- 浮躁？ - 因为她的皮肤是由叶子做成的
- Flappy? - Because her skin is made of a leaf.
-  比喻 - 是吗?
- Metaphor. - Is it?
昨天 我拉了一坨形状像鱼的便便
Yesterday, I made a poop shaped like a fish.
即使是我的屁股 也能用来作比喻
Even my butt, is capable of making an analogy.
发生了什么事
What's happening?
液体渗进了他的肺里
The fluid is in his lungs.
P13
P13.
陛下正在接受治疗 很快我们的试管就有了突破
Sire was in the middle of his treatment, soon we had a breakthrough with that tube.
也许明天我们应该继续
Perhaps then we should resume tomorrow...
我们明天不复工了 不
We will not resume tomorrow, no!
P13
P13.
你在这啊
There you are.
哈罗
Hello.
你是怎么知道微氨基蛋白的  P13
How did you know about the microsamino proteins, P13?
里面发生了什么？
What happened in there?
为什么
Why?
你怎么知道的 P13
How did you know, P13?
这是过滤太少了
It was too little filtration.
在高温下 是的 我们知道  我们解决了这个问题
In the hyperthermic, yes, we know. We fixed that.
但你是怎么知道的？
But how did you know?
我制造了你
I made you!
你怎么知道的
How did you know!?
因为它奏效了
Because it worked.
它奏效了
It worked...
愤怒 消失了
The rage, is gone.
我们拥有了 一直追求的和平生物...
We have the peaceful creatures we always sought...
准备住进新世界
Ready to inhabit the new world.
我们要去新世界了
We're going to the new world?
哦 ...我们？
Oh... we?
看看你
Look at you.
就好像你是被那些胖乎乎的孩子们拼凑在一起一样
It's if you were cobbled together by fat-fingered children.
你怎么可能是一个完美物种的一部分呢？
How could you be part of a perfect species?
你只是一 ...
You're simply a...
一堆错误   是我们可以从那些真正重要的生物的困境中吸取的教训
medley of mistakes we could learn from in the plight of the creatures that truly mattered.
第89批
Batch 89...
从来就不是为新世界准备的 P13
was never meant for the new world, P13.
你可以弄清楚细胞质过滤系统的复杂工作原理
You could figure out the complex workings of cytoplasmic filtration systems,
但你不会明白的是
but you couldn't figure out that?
你那个大脑…
But that brain...
这个 我很想做进一步的研究
That, I'd like to study further.
为早上的手术和移除做好准备吧
Prep it for surgery and removal in the morning.
第89批次剩下的呢 陛下
What about the rest of batch 89, sire?
把它们烧成灰烬
Incinerate them.
他快死了  我们需要那个秘钥
He's dying. We need that passkey.
我们的时间不多了
We don't have long.
我们到了
We've arrived.
(反地球)
这儿看起来就像... 家
That looks just like... home.
这就像是地球的复制品
It's like a replica of Earth.
这没有道理啊
It makes no sense.
大气适合居住  重力相差不大
Atmosphere is habitable. Gravity is and/or minus one.
哈罗  我们没有恶意
Hello. We mean you no harm.
听我说 他只是想把球扔给她
Listen to me, he was just trying to throw her back the ball.
拜托   别
Please, no...
格鲁特  变怪兽
Groot! Full kaiju!
- 别变怪兽  - 我是格鲁  特
- Not full kaiju! - I am Groooooot!
没有理由害怕的
No reason to be afraid.
下来 格鲁特
Get down, Groot!
各位 没事的 嘿
Everybody, it's okay. Hey.
嗨 我们不是来伤害你的
Hi. We're not here to harm you.
好的   你看
Okay... you see?
给你膝盖用的
For your knee.
我们只是想救我们的朋友
We just need to save our friend.
它不属于这里
It doesn't belong here.
我要用索维林人的方式训练它
I will train it in the ways of the Sovereign.
我会训练他不要那样做
I will train him not to do that.
这简直是亵渎神灵
The blasphemy even having it here.
杀了它 马上
Kill it! Now.
我是术士 妈妈 我受够了被人使唤
I'm the Warlock, mum, and I'm done of being ordered around.
卡魔拉在这里
Gamora is here.
这意味着松鼠也…
Which means the squirrel is, also...
为了拯救我们自己 我们必须抢先一步把它带到至高进化那里
To save ourselves, we must bring it to the High Evolutionary before his own people do.
是 是 坐  我们坐
Yeah, yeah. Sit. Let's sit.
好的
Okay.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
这不是粗鲁 这个就是这样用的
It's not rude, it's what it's here for.
德拉克斯 坐起来！笨蛋
Drax, sit up! Idiot.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们的朋友
Our friend,
他快死了
he's dying.
我们爱我们的朋友
We love our friend.
但他快死了
But he is dying.
他不是快死了  而是已经死了
That's not dying. That's already dead.
他们会认为他已经死了
They'll think he's already dead.
他们会认为我们是来报仇的
They'll think we are here on a quest for revenge.
德拉克斯 坐起来
Drax, sit up!
- 这个就是这样用的 - 德拉克斯 并不是
- That's what it's here for. - Drax, it isn't.
这个是为人们肩并肩坐在一起而设计的 把你的靴子从枕头上拿开
It's made for people to sit shoulder to shoulder right next to each other. Get your boots off their pillows.
我很难相信它没有多重用途
I find it hard to believe it doesn't have a multiple purpose.
我很抱歉 我的朋友是个笨蛋
I'm sorry. My friend is a dumbass.
这表情就像你死了一样
That's the same as your dying.
你为什么事事挑剔?
Why do you criticize everything?
那为什么沙发这么长呢?
So why is the couch long then?
这声音跟“死了”是完全不同的
It was a totally different sound.
不  并不是  呃  表示死了 呃 表示笨蛋   瞧  完全一样
No it isn't. Ugh! Dying... ugh! Dumbass... see? It's the same.
好了  伙计们   我可以继续了吗
Alright, guys. Can I proceed, please?
我们正在救我们的朋友
We're trying to save our friend.
德拉克斯 我看到你了
Drax, I see you.
我知道你现在根本不明白这一切
I understand that none of this makes any sense to you right now.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help
帮我们找一个人
in finding a man.
我来画一下 我要画出我们要找的人
I'm gonna draw. I'm gonna draw the man that we're looking for.
看到她头上的东西了吗?  他也有那个东西…
You see the thing on her head? He has a thing...
真是太好喝了
That is delightful.
就是这样
There you go.
你见过这个人吗?
Have you seen this man?
画得太好了
That's very good.
请稍后把它挂在我的公寓里好吗？
Can I have that later to hang on my apartment, please?
好的 谢谢
Yeah, thank you.
他的名字吗？ 他的名字叫莫提奥？
His name? His name is Motio?
很多莫提奥   那里
Many Motios. There?
在金字塔上
At the pyramid.
那是你的车吗
Is that your car in the driveway?
德拉克斯 和火箭呆在一起
Drax, stay here with Rocket.
看着他 他们要找的就是他
Watch him, that's who they're coming for.
- 我也想去  - 不
- I want to come! - No.
曼提斯 看着德拉克斯
Mantis, watch Drax.
格鲁特 你应该知道该怎么处理这些
Groot, you know what to do with these.
按下去
Push down on it.
- 什么 - 按下去
- What?  - Push it down.
我正在按住它
I am pushing down on it.
按那个按键
Push the button.
看起来你在按钥匙孔
It looks like you're pushing the keyhole.
- 什么  - 把手下面有一个按钮
- What? - There's a button under the handle.
按下去
Press that in.
好了 现在呢
Okay. Now what?
打开该死的车门
Open the fucking door!
真是个愚蠢的设计
That is a stupid design.
而且你的说明 表达得很不清楚
And the instructions were very unclear!
我们去拿秘钥 拯救我们的朋友
Let's get that passkey and save our friend.
我离开地球的时候才八岁? 我怎么会比你更懂开这种车呢?
I was 8 years old when I left Earth, okay? Why would I know any more about driving one of these than you do?
别说你是自愿的
Don't say you're volunteering.
- 你想让我开车吧?  那我来开  - 不!
- You want me to drive? I'll drive. - No!
我不想让你开车  我能行
I don't want you to drive. I got this.
你一定是一只非常忠诚的宠物
You must be a really loyal pet
因为他们愿意为你不顾一切
if they're willing to do all this for you.
这就是完美的社会吗
This is the perfect society?
陛下
Sire...
这一个已经跑了两个小时了 一点汗都没有
This one has been running for two hours without breaking a sweat.
太不可思议了 我…
That's incredible, if I...
他们每天只需要30卡路里的热量 一周只睡一小时   他们总是很快乐
They can survive on 30 calories a day an hour of sleep a week. They are always happy.
而且他们可以在不到两分钟的时间内重新连接碳三烯酸核心
And they can rewire a carbonetrix core in under two minutes.
但她准备好迎接新社群了吗?
But will she be ready for the new colony?
陛下  他们来了
Sire, they're here.
我们到了
Here we go.
- 我们是来看…  - 至高进化在等你们
- We're here to see... - The High Evolutionary's expecting you.
这意味着这是陷阱
Which means it is a trap.
这是一场较量
It's a face-off.
她得待在这里
She stays here.
- 为什么? - 我们这禁枪
- Why? - Policy against weaponry.
而你的手臂是一把枪
And your arm is a gun.
- 他很干净  - 我们走
- He's clean. - Let's go.
会没事的
It'll be okay.
快走
Move it!
你还好吗 火箭
Are you okay, Rocket?
我和火箭  现在 玩
Me and Rocket play now?
现在不行 地板
I can't right now, Floor.
- 你在干什么? - 他们不会放我们自由的
- What are you doing? - They ain't gonna set us free.
是的 火箭 我们随时都可能去新世界
Yes they are, Rocket. We're going to the new world any day now.
不 这不可能是真的
No, that can't be true.
就是
It is.
他们想在早上把我们都杀了
They wanna kill us all in the morning.
- 什么 - 什么
- What? - What?
但我会解决的
But I'm gonna fix it.
那是什么?
What is that?
这是一把钥匙
It's a key.
我要用它把我们都救出去
I'm gonna use it to get us all outta here.
我不知道这样做是否明智 火箭
I don't know if that's wise, Rocket.
我 火箭 离开 万岁 永远的朋友
Me, Rocket, leave! Hurray, friends forever!
就在走廊尽头
Just down that hall,
那里有船
there's ships.
我知道  如果  我们能找到一艘 我就能驾驶它
I know that if we can get to one, I can pilot it.
然后我们会一起飞走
And then we'll all fly away together.
我们四个 就像我们一直说的 好吗?
The four of us, just like we always said, okay?
好吗
Okay?
火箭  天空 天空 天空
Rocket! Sky, sky, sky!
你做到了
You did it!
真是太好了
It really is good to have
是的 我就猜到你会这么做
Yes, I imagined you'd do something like this.
回笼子里去 P13
Back in the cage, P13.
天空
Sky...
火箭 长牙 快走!   火箭 长牙 快走!
Rocket, Teefs, Floor go now! Rocket, Teefs, Floor go now!
Q12和P13从它们的围栏里逃了出来
Q12 and P13 escaped from their pens.
Q12已全部失效
Q12 is neutralized, but...
P13 还在外面
P13 is still out,
所以我需要帮助
so I'll need assistance.
火箭 长牙 地板 快走
Rocket, Teefs, Floor go now!
记住 不要伤到它的大脑
Remember, not to bruise its brain.
好了 P13
Alright, P13!
你赢得了哭泣比赛 现在回到笼子里
You win the crying contest, now back in the cage!
火箭 长牙 地板 快走
Rocket, Teefs, Floor go now!
快走  火箭 拜托
Just go! Rocket, please!
火箭 火箭
Rocket! Rocket!
在这里  快点
Down here, hurry!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我有种不好的预感
I have a bad feeling about this.
彼得让你待在这里
Peter just told you to stay here.
是啊 那是他的错
Yeah well, that's his fault.
他现在应该知道我从来不会听命于人
He should know by now that I never do anything that anyone ever tells me.
我们得保护火箭
We need to protect Rocket.
是的 没错
Yeah, that's right.
所以上车吧 然后我们骑车回飞船上去
So hop on. And we'll ride back to the ship.
只骑到那边而已吗？
Just right over there?
是
Yeah.
德拉克斯  嘿 别犯浑了
Drax! Hey, stop being a jerk.
你  嘿 是的  就是你
You! Hey! Yeah, you.
我来拿秘钥 那东西就在你头上
I take it the passkey, it's in that thing on your head.
我建议反对暴力
I would advise against aggression.
哦  现在有时间陪我了吗?
Oh, got time for me now?
你的朋友 有一次  曾占过我便宜
Your friend once took advantage.
我吸取了教训
I learned my lessons.
我把一小部分的心智能力放在我自己的身上
I aimed some small part of my mental capacity back in my own direction.
现在 操控重力本身就已满足了我的奇思妙想
And now, gravity itself serves my whims.
战猪 上
War Pig, now.
你一定对反地球很熟悉
You must find Counter-Earth familiar.
- 反地球 -  很多年前我去过你们的星球
- Counter-Earth. - I visited your planet many years ago.
地球早就不是我的星球了
Earth hasn't been my planet in a long time.
你的人民有…
Your people had...
美好的精神
Wonderful spirit.
艺术、音乐和文学
The art, music and literature,
是全宇宙中最优秀的
were some of the finest in the universe.
如果没有无知和偏执 地球将是一个美妙的地方
Earth would be a fabulous place were it not for the ignorance and bigotry.
- 好吧 - 它启发了我创造反地球
- Okay.  - It inspired me to create Counter-Earth.
- 我不在乎…  -  都是好的 没有坏的
- I don't care... -  All of the good and none of the bad.
我不需要再听一个无能的疯子讲话
I don't need another speech by some impotent whackjob
他的母亲并不爱他  却为他征服宇宙找理由
whose mother didn't love him, rationalizing why he needs to conquer the universe.
我不是想征服宇宙…
I'm not trying to conquer the universe...
我是在完善它
I'm perfecting it.
搞什么...
What the...
把浣熊放下
Drop the badger.
我只想要密钥
I just want the passkey.
那就给我89P13
Then bring me 89P13.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
他说:吸我的...
He says suck my
你为什么这么生气
Why are you so angry?
因为我知道你对我们的朋友做了什么
Because I know what you did to our friend.
我所做的一切 都是为了宇宙的美好
Anything I've done, I've done for the betterment of the universe.
新闻快讯 爱因斯坦  美好的宇宙通常不包括一群章鱼向长着蟑螂头的人出售冰毒
Newsflash, Einstein. Better universes generally don't include a bunch of octopuses selling meth to guys with cockroach heads.
确实不包括
They do not.
这就是为什么 就像我以前做过很多次的那样
Which is why, as I've done many times before...
我要把它全部夷为平地
I'm going to have to raze it all,
然后重新开始
and start again.
什么
What?
我抓到了89P13 正在路上
I got 89P13 and I'm on my way.
我们找到目标了
We're in possession of the subject.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot?
杀光他们
Kill them all.
停下
Stay.
我说停下
I said stay.
什么 你想让我把你留下 这样那个妈妈就可以领养你了吗？
What? Did you want me to leave you back so that mother could filet you?
停下
Stay.
搞什么鬼 我们可是为同一个老板工作
What the hell, we're working for the same boss.
是的 但我需要功劳 伙计  为了拯救我的整个文明
Yes, but I need the credit, chum. To save my entire civilization.
所以 做个好怪人…之类的事情
So be a good creepy... thing,
然后 退后
and back off.
妈妈
Mother.
Mother!
曼提斯 德拉克斯 回话
Mantis, Drax, come in.
曼提斯 德拉克斯
Mantis, Drax?
- 呃 嘿 - 我要你把飞船开过来 马上!
- Uh, hey. - I need you to bring the ship here, now!
我们不能这么做 因为…
Well, we can't do that exactly, because...
我们不在船上
We're not in the ship.
那你到底在哪儿?
Then where the hell are you?
- 星云  回话 - 卡魔拉
- Nebula, come in. - Gamora!
马上起飞!  和火箭赶紧离开这个星球
Take off now! Get yourself and Rocket off the planet!
这是什么型号的船啊
What kind of ship is this?
这很有趣 真的
That's amusing, really.
你到底有多蠢
How stupid are you?
这显然是个陷阱
It was so obviously a trap.
这不是陷阱 这是较量
It's not a trap, it's a face-off!
现在 杀光他们
Now, kill them all.
你手里拿的是什么
What do you have in your hand?
手雷
Grenade!
我是格鲁特
I am Groot!
不  不  求求你
No, no, no, no, no, please.
求求你放过我 嘿 放过我
Please spare me. Hey, spare me.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
那还为时过早
That'd be premature.
相当新颖的逃生计划
Quite a novel escape plan.
头朝下跳进一个爆炸的星球
Jumping headfirst into an exploding planet.
你会害咱俩送命的
You'll kill us both!
不一定
Not both!
我们为什么要这样做
Why are we doing this?
奎尔和格鲁特在里面！我们必须把他们弄出来
Quill and Groot are inside! We have to get them out.
格鲁特
Groot.
无论谁在驾驶舱 快启动刹车
Whoever's in the cockpit, activate the brake.
转向机构卡住了
The steering mechanism is stuck!
好吧 用力拉
Well, pull harder!
快走
Let's go!
呼吸困难
It's hard to breathe.
我们正在进入太空
We are entering space.
噢 讨厌
Oh, piss off.
什么样的怪物会屠杀一个文明
What kind of monster slaughters a civilization?
- 曼提斯和德拉克斯在哪里?  - 我不知道
- Where are Mantis and Drax?  - I do not know!
你们很幸运 我推倒了那扇门
You're lucky I was able to knock down that door.
火箭和卡魔拉 可能因为你而死掉
Rocket and Gamora, are probably dead because of you!
- 我不知道 - 哦 你不知道吗？
- I didn't know. - Oh, you didn't know?
你什么时候才能让自己长进点  你这个傻瓜小丑
When are you gonna stop using the excuse of being some big dumb clown
你什么贡献都没有 却总让我们替你收拾烂摊子!
for contributing nothing, and the rest of us having to carry your slack!
别推他  你没有权利推他
Don't push him! You don't have the right to push him.
而你 你也好不到哪里去
And you, you're no better.
我们唯一能指望你的 就是当某人表现出弱点时 你会在他脑子里安慰他
The only thing we can count on you for, is when someone shows weakness, you'll be right there to support it.
好吧 我不在乎
Fine, I don't care.
我知道你   总是找别人的毛病   好让自己感觉好点
I know you need to find fault in everyone else to make yourself feel okay.
所以在我身上找吧
So find it in me.
啊 去死吧 曼
Oh, go to hell, Mant-!
但你没有权利推他
But you don't have the right to push him!
他愚蠢又不是他的错
It's not his fault he's stupid.
他是个累赘
He's a liability.
他让我们开怀大笑 他爱我们  他怎么会是个累赘呢
He makes us laugh and he loves us. How is that a liability?
你所关心的只是智力和能力
All you care about is intelligence and competence.
不确定我是否欣赏这种辩护
Not sure I appreciate this defense.
他有悲伤...
He has sadness...
但他是你们中唯一一个不恨自己的人
But he's the only one of you who doesn't hate himself.
我不在乎他是否愚蠢
I don't care if he's stupid.
你认为我愚蠢吗？
Do you think I'm stupid?
是的
Yes.
忘了吧
Forget.
哈！你们很幸运 我用我惊人的力量把门撞开了
Hah! You're lucky I was able to knock down that door with my incredible strength.
奎尔
Quill?
奎尔  你在吗
Quill, are you there?
我的翻译器里没有这种语言
This language isn't in my translator.
好的
OK.
好了  火箭 加油
Alright, Rocket. Go.
莱拉
Lylla?
朋友
Friend.
好的 好的
OK, OK...
好的 开始了
OK, here we go.
这不对劲
This isn't right.
不 不 不  这很好  它会起作用的  它在起作用了
No, no, no. It's good. It's gonna work. It's working.
它得快点
It needs to be faster.
对不起 真的很抱歉
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
- 火箭  - 我让你失望了
- Rocket. - I let you down.
我害你被杀了
I got you killed.
你是对的
You were right.
天空很美
The sky is beautiful.
而且直到永远
And it is forever.
而且我一直在和朋友们飞行
And I've been flying with our friends.
我能来吗
Can I come?
是的
Yes.
不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no.
不
No!
-  拜托 -  奎尔
- Come on! - Quill.
不
No!
-  奎尔 - 不
- Quill... - No!
- 我不会失去他的  - 他走了
- I'm not gonna lose him. - He is gone.
我不会让他走的
I'm not letting him go!
但不是现在
But not yet.
你在这里仍然有目标
You still have a purpose here.
什么目标
A purpose for what?
他们无缘无故造了我们
They made us for nothing!
做完实验后又把我们毁掉
Just stupid experiments to be thrown away!
是那双手造就了我们…
There are the hands that made us...
还有一双手引导着这双手
and then there are the hands that guide the hands.
我心爱的浣熊
My beloved raccoon...
这个故事一直都是你的 你只是不知道而已
This story has been yours all along. You just didn't know it.
我不是浣熊
I'm not a raccoon.
秘钥通了
The passkey's going through!
星云在哪儿
Where's Nebula?
她 她  呃
She, she's, uh....
因为她的代码在你身后的通讯系统上
Because her code is on the comm behind you.
- 什么…星云? -你在哪里?
- What... Nebula? - Where are you?
- 哦 谢天谢地!  - 我们是来救你离开的
- Oh, thank God! - We're here to get you out of here.
- 离开哪里? - 至高进化的飞船!
- Out of where? - The High Evolutionary's ship!
不 我下了船
No, I got off the ship.
- 你说什么?  - 等等 你在哪儿?
- You what?  - Wait, where are you?
在船上
On the ship!
-  在船上? - 我没有说谎
- On the ship?  - I didn't lie.
- 你为什么在船上? - 显然是为了救你!
- Why are you on the ship? - To save you, obviously!
不 我让你回去的 你应该了解我的
No, I told you to go back. You gotta know by now
我总是能在关键时刻想出办法 摆脱困境的
I always figure out a clever way to get out of a fix!
-  代我向他问好 - 真的吗?
- Tell him I said hi.  - Really?
告诉他我们来救他了
Tell him we're coming to save him.
集中注意力或者和孩子们一起玩  要么这样 要么那样
Pay attention or play with the kids. One or the other.
- 和孩子们一起玩? - 你怎么出来的?
- Play with the kids? - How did you get out?
- 这并不重要…… - 我是格鲁特
- That's not really important... - I am Groot.
不带降落伞从1000英尺高空跳下摔死  是摆脱困境的好办法吗?
Jumping a 1000 feet to your death without a parachute is a clever way of getting out of a fix?
你们都是在瞎编木头人说的话 对吧?
You're all just making up stuff that he's saying, right?
重要的是我们都没事
The important thing is we're all okay.
火箭
Rocket?
是的 他在这里 他好了
Yes, he's here and he's okay.
火箭 我们非常爱你 很高兴你还活着
Rocket, we love you very much and we're happy you're alive.
那你们就是白痴了
Well that makes you idiots, then.
他说得对
He's right about that.
回你们的笼子里去
Back in your cages!
星云
Nebula?
星云  回话
Nebula, come in.
那么 你想参加格斗比赛 是吗
So, you'd like to joust, would you?
下地狱去吧 你个恶心的混蛋
Go to hell, you sick son of a bitch.
那些人都是你杀的
You killed all of those people.
就像我对你的朋友一样
As I will your friends.
我把坐标发给你
I'm sending you the coordinates.
他们会死的  除非你把我想要的东西还给我
They will die unless you bring me what is mine!
去你的 你这拉皮脸  机械战警  骷髅怪人 紫薯精 混蛋
Screw you, you stretch-faced, Robocop looking, Skeletor wannabe, purple-nurple, piece of
他挂断了
He hung up.
你觉得呢？
You think?
1966年
1966...
苏联人把我送上了火箭
The Soviets put me on a rocket
我很清楚我再也回不来了  我会死在一个火热的死球里
knowing full well I never to return and I will die in a fiery ball of death.
即使是苏联人也从不做的一件事
The one thing even Soviets never do,
就是叫我“坏狗”
is call me "bad dog."
哦 我的天 忘了那句话吧
Oh, my God, just let it go.
克拉格林 拜托 收回那句话吧
Kraglin, please, just take it back.
这简直要了我们的命
This is killing us.
事实上 如果她真是一只坏狗 我就无法收回那句话
I can't take it back if she is, in fact, a bad dog.
它从未停止过伤害
It never stops hurting.
- 克拉格林 - 噢 嘿 彼得
- Kraglin. - Oh, hey, Pete.
我们得去救星云 曼提斯和德拉克斯
We need to save Nebula, Mantis and Drax,
我们需要你的帮助
and we need your help.
我吗
Me?
是你把他弄丢的 你个笨蛋
You're the one who lost him, you twit!
地狱之子听到了 陛下
The hellspawn heard it, sire.
- 但...  - 但  但  但  但  但  但
- But... - But, but, but, but, but!
令人作呕的词
That rancid word.
我只是想知道 直接去新殖民地
I'm merely wondering whether it might be wiser,
不要卷入不必要的冲突 是否更明智
to go directly to the new colony and not engage in unnecessary conflict.
他们可以在不到两分钟的时间内重新连接碳三烯酸核心
They can rewire a carbonetrix core in under two minutes.
但那是什么 维姆
But what is that, Vim?
- 机械刻板 - 机械刻板
- Rote memorization. - Rote memorization!
在人类数百年的创造中 只有一项发明 是真正的发明
In hundreds of years of our creations, only one has known true invention.
只有一项
One.
其余的都是垃圾
Putrid in every other way,
除了89P13之外
but 89P13 had that.
是的 陛下
Yes, sire.
无法思考的民众
A populace unable to think,
没有思想的平民   将会死亡
what hasn't yet been thought, will die.
为什么我们需要89P13的大脑
And why we need 89P13's brain
这样我们才能在进入新殖民地之前
so we can transfer that trait into these creatures
将这种特性转移到这些生物身上
before we go to the new colony.
其他的都不重要
Nothing else matters.
他们是怎么到这里来的?
How did they get down here?
彼得会试着去太空港
Peter will be trying to get to the spaceport.
他不知道孩子们的事
He doesn't know about the children.
你
You!
我们需要你告诉船上所有的孩子远离右舷的墙
We need you to let all the other children onboard know to stay away from the starboard walls!
他们只知道三个奇怪的单词 其中两个是啾啾
They know three freaking words and two of them are joob.
不   听我说
No! Listen to me.
你需要和其他孩子谈谈
You need to talk to the other children.
所有人都在这里 告诉他们
All of them here, and tell them,
远离那个可怕的 -
to stay away, from the freakin' -
你到底在干什么 曼提斯
What the hell are you doing, Mantis?
我在解释啊 笨蛋
Explaining it, dickhead!
你们吓到他们了
You're scaring them.
你们好 白痴们
Hello, dumb idiots.
我曾有个像你一样的小女孩
I had a little girl like you.
你知道她以前喜欢什么吗?
You know what she used to like?
她喜欢我发出猴子的声音
She liked when I made monkey noises.
那怎么会是猴子
How is that a monkey?
难倒我了
Beats me.
他们会告诉其他孩子离右舷的墙远点
They're gonna tell the other kids to stay away from the starboard wall.
你为什么不告诉我们 你一直都懂他们的语言
Why didn't you tell us you knew their language this whole time?
你为什么不问我呢
Why didn't you ask?
这可能是徒劳的 奎尔
This could be futile, Quill.
他太强大了
He's too powerful.
好吧 那我们就死定了
Well then, I guess we'll die trying.
你这么拼命到底是图个啥呀？
What is dying trying gonna accomplish?
或者我们可以直接给他一只浣熊
Or we can just give him the badger.
我们的风格 就是拼命三郎
Our thing, is dying trying.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我已经知道你是谁了
I know who you are already!
请随时留在货物区
Feel free to stay behind in the cargo area.
我不会把我妹妹留给那个混蛋
I'm not leaving my sister with that jackass.
这是你的
This you?
从你的包里掉出来
Fell out of your bag.
说干就干
Let's do this.
等等
Wait...
你几乎不得不佩服他们的勇气
You almost have to admire their pluck.
陛下
Sire.
你好啊 你这个变态
Howdy there, you freakin' creep.
- 后退 - 是的 陛下
- Back up! - Yes, sire.
轮到你了 史丁米
You're on, Steemie.
第一枪管
First barrel.
第二枪管
Second barrel.
第三枪管
Third barrel.
第四枪管
Fourth barrel.
右满舵
Hard starboard.
发射
And, fire!
他们突破了太空港
They've breached the spaceport.
其中一个持有89P13号实验对象
One of them holds subject 89P13.
释放所有的地狱之子
Release the hellspawn, all of them.
陛下 地狱之子的诞生只是为了保卫新世界
Sire, the hellspawn were created solely to defend the new colony.
马上执行
Do it now!
把89P13给我抓来
Get me 89P13,
然后杀光死亡神头里的人
and kill everyone in the head of that dead god!
太空港已完全开放 舰长 但我们只有这些武器
Spaceport wide open, Cap'n, but that armaments was all we had.
火箭 格鲁特 快 快
Rocket, Groot, go, go!
进入那个太空港
Get inside that spaceport.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
嗷 拜托
Aww, come on!
克拉格林 我们被渗透了!
Kraglin, we have been infiltrated!
准备交易
Open the pit.
陛下 我们的交易谈判几乎没本钱了
Sire, our bargaining power will be gone.
阿比利斯克
Abilisks!
我的天
Good God...
这边走
This way!
再往前走一步 这个奇怪的东西就会被干掉
One more step and this weird thing gets it!
不要鲁莽
Don't be rash.
你刚才在编什么程序?
What were you programming?
自毁代码
Self-destruction code.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
没事的
It's okay.
曼提斯 停下
Mantis, stop.
它们吃的是电池 不是人
They eat batteries, not people.
也许他们只是害怕我们  对它做的坏事
Maybe they're just scared of what we are gonna do to them.
我们不会伤害你的
We're not gonna hurt you.
一切都会好起来的
Everything is going to be okay.
用你的真心  孩子
Use your heart, boy.
一条狗
A dog?
是的
Yeah.
它是一只好狗
She's a good dog.
我就知道 你相信我是只好狗
I knew you believe I'm good dog.
好吧 好吧 放开我 你这个白痴
Alright, alright, alright. Get off me you idiot.
陛下 我们必须撤退 飞船要完了
Sire, we must retreat. The ship is going down.
太空港有入侵者
The spaceport has intruders.
去 看看有没有89P13
Go, see if one of them is 89P13.
陛下 你对这只动物有一种非理性的执念
Sire, you have an irrational obsession with this animal.
看在上帝的份上 你必须停下来
You must stop for God's sake
从来就没有上帝！ 这就是我开创事业的原因！
There is no god! That's why I stepped in!
管制员 我要接手阿雷特号指挥权
Controller, I am taking command of the Arete.
脱离飞船所有受损部分
Disengage all damaged sectors of the ship.
然后撤退
And retreat...
注意
Attention,
所有人员
all personnel...
入侵者已经登船
Intruders have boarded the ship.
前往右舷太空港
Head to the starboard spaceport.
给我 89P13
Bring me 89P13.
然后杀死剩下的
And kill the rest.
我们进去 救出曼提斯 星云和德拉克斯
We go in there, we get Mantis, Nebula and Drax.
我们进去 干掉他们 然后离开
We move in, we get them, and get out.
看起来酷吗?
Did that look cool?
好了
Okay.
新计划  我们现在赶紧离开这里
New gameplan. We get the hell outta here now.
这艘船上有成千上万的生物
There are thousands of creatures on this ship.
- 其中许多是儿童 - 我们要做一个好的啾啾
- Many of them are children. - We need to be good joob-joob.
它的意思是“朋友”
It means friends.
如果我们想活命 就得马上离开
If we want to live, we have to leave now.
整个塔台随时都会倒塌
This whole rig is gonna go down any second.
如果我们不帮助他们 他们都会死的
They will all die, if we don't help them.
我不想再跑了
I'm done runnin'.
甲板上有个大洞
There's a big hole up in the deck.
如果我们能把它和虚无之地连接起来
If we can connect that to Knowhere,
我们就能把幸存者带到安全的地方
we can lead the survivors to safety.
星云和我去开飞船
Nebs and me will pilot the ship.
你们去拯救所有的高级生命
You guys save all the higher life forms.
你好, 傻孩子
Hello, moron.
来吧
Come on!
跟着我 来吧
Follow me, come on!
来吧
Come on!
走 走 走
Go, go, go!
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
嗯 往这边走…
Um, this way to...
谢谢你
Thank you.
好的 不用客气
Yes, you're welcome.
我对着你身后可怕的东西尖叫  不是你
I was screaming at something scary behind you. Not you.
你看起来真的很酷
You look really cool.
你想杀我就杀吧 但祝你能顺利离开这里
Kill me if you want, but then good luck getting out of here.
让他走吧  那家伙是我们唯一的机会
Let him go. That guy's our only chance.
我找到了足够大的破洞
I got a space big enough to get through.
我得看看能不能把它换成可穿透的护盾
I gotta find out if I can change it to a permeable shield.
我不会开这破玩意 控制装置都坏了
I can't fly this freakin' thing. The controls are all screwed.
我来吧
I'll do it.
去帮助其他人吧 等等 把你的对讲机给我
Go help the others. Wait, give me your comm.
克拉格林 我从这边驾驶
Kraglin, I'll pilot from this side.
星云 王者归来了
Nebula, back in action.
快点  快点  快点
Come on, come on, come on!
等等  等等  等等  等等  等等  停下 停下
Wait, wait. Wait, wait, wait. Stop, stop!
那些是孩子吗?
Are those kids?
好吧 科斯莫 对接起来
Okay, Cosmo, stitch it up.
它需要密封 孩子们才能通过
It needs to be airtight for the kids to make it across!
锁定中 舰长
Locking up, captain.
走 马上  走
Go, now, go.
一个一个来 一个一个来
One by one. One by one.
接上了  正在下坠
Landing in, and headed down.
这边走 这边走
This way, this way.
为什么
Why?
你为什么要这么做?  我之前一直想杀你
Why are you doing this? I tried to kill you.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
他说 每个人都应该有第二次机会
He says everyone deserves a second chance.
你是如此地强大
You are so strong.
快点  你们怎么这么慢
Come on! Why are you so slow?
火箭在哪里
Where is Rocket?
(蓝博野生动物保护中心)
(原产地：北美 | 领域：动物 | 门类：脊索动物门)
(浣熊)
不
No!
你以为你能摆脱我吗
You thought you could escape me?
不
No!
你觉得  没有我  你还有价值吗?
You think you have some worth in and of yourself without me?
不
No!
你真是个讨厌鬼
You are an abomination!
你只不过是我在路上踏出的一小步
Nothing more than a step, on my path!
你这个变态的小怪物
You freakish little monster!
你怎么敢认为你比我强
How dare you think you are more?
8-9-P-1-3
8-9-P-1-3.
我叫火箭  火箭浣熊
The name's Rocket. Rocket Raccoon.
他的脸掉了
His face came off.
是一个面具
It's a mask.
看看你对我做了什么
Look what you did to me.
为了什么?
For what?
我想做的…
All I wanted to do...
只是让事物变得完美
was to make things perfect.
你不是想让事物变得完美
You didn't want to make things perfect.
你只是讨厌事物本来的样子
You just hated things the way they are.
杀了他
Kill him.
为什么
Why?
因为我是他妈的银河系的守护者
Because I'm a freakin' Guardian of the Galaxy.
我们得马上离开这里
We have to get out of here, now.
我们必须拯救他们
We have to save them
我们把所有的孩子都带上了
We've got all the kids on board.
不 彼得 还有剩下的
No, Pete. The rest of them.
快点 快点  快走
Come on! Come on, move.
快走
Move it.
快点
Come on.
快点  快点
Come on, come on.
我以为我们只局限于高级生命形式
I thought we were limiting ourselves to the higher life forms.
我也是
Me, too.
加油 宝贝  加油 宝贝
Go babies. Go, babies.
加油
Go!
我坚持不住了
I cannot hold... much...
奎尔
Quill!
赶快
Hurry!
彼得
Peter!
Peter.
看起来
Did that...
酷吗？
... look cool?
来吧
Come on.
科斯莫
Cosmo.
我没事
I'm okay.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
谢谢 告诉他们我是对的…
Thanks, just tell them I'm gonna be right...
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
是的 和你一起工作也很愉快
Yeah. It's good working with you too.
嘿 卡魔拉 准备好了吗?
Hey Gamora, are you ready?
是的
Yeah.
你知道的 我终究不是你记忆中的那个人
You know I'm still not who you want me to be.
我知道
I know.
但你的本性并没有那么坏
But who you are ain't so bad.
我们以前一定很有趣
I bet we were fun.
就像你不会相信的那样
Like you wouldn't believe.
好了
All right.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我想我需要和大家谈谈
I think I need to talk to everybody.
所以 你要离开了?
So, you're gonna leave?
我母亲在我8岁的时候去世了
My mother died in front of me when I was 8 years old
从那以后我一直在逃避
and I have been running ever since.
我需要花点时间
I'm gonna need to take some time.
学习如何游泳
Learn how to swim.
我也是
I as well.
我爱你们大家
I love you all.
真的
I do.
但在我的一生中 我做了伊戈想要我做的事
But my whole life, I did whatever Ego wanted.
然后 我又做了守护者该做的事
And then I did whatever the Guardians wanted.
我要出去走走 去发现我的新目标
I need to go out and discover what I want.
- 我和你一起走  - 不带德拉克斯
- I will come with you. - No Drax.
这才是重点
That's the whole point.
但你需要有人保护你
But you need someone to protect you.
- 我不要  - 我会换个方式
- I don't. - Not in a bad way.
只是担心你不可思议的弱点
Just because of your incredible weakness.
哦 天啊 你真让人沮丧
Oh, my God, you're so frustrating.
德拉克斯 我这儿需要你
Drax, I need you here.
我们正在建设一个新社会
We're building a new society.
我需要为那些孩子们提供一切力所能及的支持
I need all the support I can get for those children out there.
今天 我看到了真正的你
Today, I saw who you are.
你不是天生的毁灭者
You weren't born to be a destroyer.
你天生就是当爸爸的料
You were born to be a dad.
那你还会领导守护者吗?
So you'll lead the Guardians then?
不
No.
我要领导这座城市
I'm going to lead the city.
让它成为我从未有过的家
Make it the type of home I never had.
就这样吗?
So that's it?
组队结束了？
The group's over?
不
No.
银河系仍然需要守护者
The galaxy still needs its guardians.
而你 会成为一个比我更优秀的领导者…
And you, will make a better leader than I ever was...
舰长
Captain.
我爱你们 伙计们
I love you, guys.
(我回去了  这个送给你  彼得)
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
我想我可能弄错了…
I think I might be at the wrong...
我找杰森·奎尔
I'm looking for Jason Quill?
是  请进
Yes. Come in.
彼得
Pete.
嗨  外公
Hi, Grandpa.
好吧 你们最喜欢的表演团体呢?
Okay, how about your favorite musical act?
菲拉 你先来
Phyla, you first.
“小甜甜”布兰妮和科恩
Britney Spears and Korn.
- 选得好 - 我选的是一个人
- Good choices. - I gotta go with the man.
加斯·布鲁克斯
Garth Brooks.
卡朋特乐队的歌  一首烂的没有
The Carpenters did not have a single bad song.
亚德里安·比劳
Adrian Belew.
都是独唱 还有他和克里姆森国王乐队的合作
Both solo, and his work with King Crimson.
那你呢   舰长
What about you, captain?
哦 这个有点特别
Oh, this one's kinda special.
我猜它们来了
Guess they're here.
好吧
Well...
我一个人就能搞定 如果你们想放松的话
I can handle this by my lonesome if you all wanna chill.
不 不 如果我们一起上 会很快的
Nah, nah, it'll go fast if we all do it together.
格鲁特 醒醒
Groot, wake up.
你有没有为它们感到一点点难过?
Do ya ever feel a little sad for them?
是的  当然  但这些市民无法保护自己
Yeah, sure. But these townsfolk can't protect themselves.
听你的吩咐 舰长
On your word, Captain.
吩咐
Word.
如果她需要帮忙修剪草坪 我会帮她 但我觉得她的儿子应该帮忙
If she needs help mowing the lawn, I'll do it but I kinda feel like her son should help.
他会坐在门廊上看我吗?
Is he gonna sit on the porch and watch me do it?
他就像一个45岁的男人 身体健壮 而我正在修剪他的草坪
He's like, a 45 year old man, able bodied and I'm mowing his lawn...
这感觉很奇怪
It just feels weird.
别让我再发飙
Don't get me started.
哦  真的吗
Oh, really?
我有点想知道
I kinda wanna know.
星爵将回归